Arthur J. Pierpont Papers 1985.0022
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Arthur J. Pierpont Papers
undated, 1902-1931
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1985.0022
0.25 Linear Feet
Arthur Joseph Pierpont was born 3 December 1876. He was a 1895 graduate of Storrs Agricultural College, now the University of Connecticut. A noted authority on agricultural matters, Mr. Pierpont was a member of the Waterbury Milk Producers Association, Trustee of his alma mater (Connecticut Agricultural College as of 1899) and manager of the College's Gilbert Farm, a working farm in Georgetown, Connecticut, bequeathed to the College in 1906.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Mr. Pierpont's daughter, Marion Pierpont Brown, on 5 June 1985.
Arrangement
Series I: Papers (undated, 1902-1931) consists of correspondence and ephemera.
Biography
Arthur Joseph Pierpont was born 3 December 1876. He was a 1895 graduate of Storrs Agricultural College, now the University of Connecticut. Following graduation Mr. Pierpont studied business in Hartford, Connecticut, before taking advanced agricultural sciences course at Cornell University. Upon his return to Connecticut, Pierpont took over the family homestead in Waterbury, Connecticut. At Maple Hill Farm, Pierpont established one of the first Holstein herds in the state and became a leading milk producer in the Naugatuck Valley. A noted authority on agricultural matters, Mr. Pierpont was a member of the Waterbury Milk Producers Association, Trustee of his alma mater (Connecticut Agricultural College as of 1899) and manager of the College's Gilbert Farm, a working farm in Georgetown, Connecticut, bequeathed to the College in 1906.
Mr. Pierpont married Beatrice Garrigus in 1900. The Pierponts had three daughters, the eldest of whom graduated from Connecticut Agricultural College in 1924.
Mr. Pierpont died 20 September 1912.
Scope and Content
The collection consists primarily of correspondence to Mr. Pierpont on matters concerning Maple Hill Farm, Gilbert Farm, or his association with Connecticut Agricultural College>.
Connecticut (state); Agriculture; Correspondence; Publications (documents); Agriculturists; History; Photographs; Education; Storrs (inhabited place); Universities and colleges; Connecticut Agricultural College; University of Connecticut; Pierpont, Arthur J.
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1902-1931
  - Biographical information, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - undated, 1902-1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1907 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1910 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1911 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1912 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ephemera, 1906, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook--50th Anniversary and Inauguration, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)